chromeriver.com 2019-12-20

# Our Privacy Policy | Travel Expense Management

Thank you for visiting the Chrome River website and reviewing our privacy policy. This privacy policy applies to [www.chromeriver.com](https://www.chromeriver.com/), which is owned and operated by Chrome River Technologies. This privacy policy describes how Chrome River Technologies (“Chrome River”, “We”, “Us” or “Our”) collects and uses the personal information you provide on our website: [www.chromeriver.com](https://www.chromeriver.com/). It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. Our privacy policy is clear: we will collect no personal information about you when you visit our website unless you choose to provide that information to us. Here is how we handle information about your visit to our website:

This privacy policy covers only our collection, use and disclosure of information we acquire through our website [www.chromeriver.com](https://www.chromeriver.com/) (https://www.chromeriver.com) and our service platform. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Customer has engaged Chrome River Technologies.

In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, Chrome River commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information.  European Union or Swiss  individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact our Privacy Officer at: Email address: [privacy@chromeriver.com](mailto:privacy@chromeriver.com)

Chrome River  has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles to JAMS EU PRIVACY SHIELD, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit JAMS [here](https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield).

Chrome River Technologies complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield  framework and Swiss-U.S > Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Chrome River has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability.  If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

### EU/Swiss - U.S. Privacy Shield: Transfer of Personal Information

Chrome River participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU and Swiss - U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Chrome River is committed to subjecting all Personal Information received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. 

Chrome River is responsible for the processing of customer Personal Information it receives under the requirements specified by the Privacy Shield Framework.  Any  transfers from Chrome River to a third party acting as an agent on Chrome River's behalf are generated in accordance with Chrome River’s contractual obligations with its customers.  Chrome River complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of Personal Information from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

In certain situations,  Chrome River may be required to disclose Personal Information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

### Complaints

You may also be able to invoke binding arbitration for unresolved complaints but prior to initiating such arbitration, a resident of a European country including Switzerland participating in the Privacy Shield must first: (1) contact us at [privacy@chromeriver.com](mailto:privacy@chromeriver.com) and afford us the opportunity to resolve the issue; (2) seek assistance from JAMS, an alternate dispute resolution provider located in the United States; and (3) contact the U.S. Department of Commerce (either directly or through a European Data Protection Authority) and afford the Department of Commerce time to attempt to resolve the issue. [US Dept. of Commerce](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint).

Chrome River has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to JAMs. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact JAMS at https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield for more information or to file a complaint.  The services of JAMs are provided at no cost to you.

### U.S. Federal Trade Commission Enforcement

Our Privacy Shield compliance is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

### Internet Security Policy

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this computer system employs software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act.

### Information Collected and Stored Automatically

When you visit our website, we may collect your personal information such as your name, email address, phone number, company name and business email address when you contact us or when you submit a request for a demonstration or other materials through our website. If you do nothing during your visit but browse through the website, read pages or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit automatically. This information does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store only the following information about your visit and store it in log files:

  * The Internet domain (for example, chromeriver.com) and IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web) from which you access our website;
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access our site;
  * The internet service provider (ISP);
  * The date and time you access our site;
  * The clickstream data;
  * The pages you visit; and
  * If you link to this website from another website, the address of that website.

We use this information to help us make our site more useful to visitors -- to learn about the number of visitors to our site and the types of technology our visitors use. We do not track or record information about individuals and their visits. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve to improve our marketing services and site functionality. When you access our website from your mobile device, we may automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or “UDID”).

### If You Send Us Personal Information

If you choose to provide us with your personal information (for example, you register on the site to access software or you ask a question using the Contact form) we will use the information only to fulfill your request or to assess the needs of your business to determine suitable products. We do not collect personal information for any other purposes. The information you provide is not given to any private organizations or private persons.

### Information Sharing

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. Chrome River does not share information with third parties for commercial marketing. We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

We may also disclose your personal information:

as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request, if Chrome River is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information, to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

### User Access and Choice

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, delete/remove or request to deactivate it by emailing our Customer Support at [support@chromeriver.com](mailto:support@chromeriver.com) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request to access within a reasonable timeframe. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

###### **Opt-out Preferences**

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name or email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at [info@chromeriver.com](mailto:info@chromeriver.com).

We will also send you service related email announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. You do have an option to opt out of these emails, which are not promotional in nature.

### Cookies and other Tracking Technologies

Technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Chrome River and our marketing partners, affiliates, and service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the website, tracking users’ movements around the website and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies to remember users’ settings and for authentication into our online application site. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you are unable to use our online application site, but you may still access our company site.

###### **Local Storage Objects (HTML 5)**

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs.

###### **Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting**

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this website and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

### Mobile Analytics

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our mobile website. This software may record information such as how often you use the website, the events that occur within the website, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was accessed from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personal information you submit within the website.

### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information such as login credentials on the login form, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [support@chromeriver.com](mailto:support@chromeriver.com).

### Additional Information

###### **Links to 3rd Party Websites**

Our website includes links to other sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Chrome River. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

###### **Referrals**

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our website, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the website. Chrome River does not store this information.

###### **Blog**

Our website offers publicly accessible blogs. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [support@chromeriver.com](mailto:support@chromeriver.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

###### **Social Media Widgets**

Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Information Related to Data Collected through the Chrome River Service

###### **Information Related to Data Collected for our Clients**

  * Chrome River Technologies collects information under the direction of its Clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. If you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the Client that you interact with directly. We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our Clients.

###### **Access and Retention of Data Controlled by our Clients**

  * Chrome River Technologies has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to the Chrome River Technologies’ Client (the data controller). If requested to remove data we will respond within 30 days. We will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. Chrome River Technologies will retain this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### Changes to This Policy

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this privacy policy, the practices of this website or your dealings with this website, please contact us using the information below:

Chrome River Technologies  
Museum Square  
5757 Wilshire Boulevard, Suite 270  
Los Angeles, CA 90036  
E-mail: [info@chromeriver.com](mailto:info@chromeriver.com)
